<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>👋 Hi! on Angelo Basile</title>
    <link>https://anbasile.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 👋 Hi! on Angelo Basile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anbasile.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some challenges of bringing NLP models in production</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/nlp-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/nlp-in-production/</guid>
      <description>Summary &amp;ldquo;As the machine learning (ML) community continues to accumulate years of experience with live systems, a wide-spread and uncomfortable trend has emerged: developing and deploying ML systems is relatively fast and cheap, but maintaining them over time is difficult and expensive&amp;rdquo;. (Sculley, et al., 2015)
In this talk, we are going to take a look at some problems that arise when we are ready to bring NLP models to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a server for NLP models in production</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/serving-nlp-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/serving-nlp-models/</guid>
      <description>Summary In machine learning, serving a trained model means making it available for people to use it to get predictions from their data and it is a fundamental step of bringing any NLP research outcome to production.
Here we will see how to set up a high-performing inference server capable of running models saved in different formats. We will be using the TensorRT Inference Server (TRTIS from now on), developed by nvidia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using jupyter notebooks with a virtual environment</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/2017-06-25-jupyter-venv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/2017-06-25-jupyter-venv/</guid>
      <description>Summary Do you use jupyter notebooks? And virtual environment too, right? And do you know how to use them together? Ah! I got you. It is very simple: follow this guide to learn how to install a custom kernel.
Why? Using virtual environments is important:
  it helps you to maintain your system clean: don&amp;rsquo;t install system-wide libraries that you are only going to use once for a small project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un manifesto per i manuali universitari</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/2017-04-10-manifesto-manuali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/2017-04-10-manifesto-manuali/</guid>
      <description>Allen Downey è docente di informatica presso l&amp;rsquo;Olin College (Needham, Massachusetts - USA) e autore di una fortunata serie di manuali di statistica. Qualche anno fa ha scritto un bel manifesto per i nuovi manuali universitari: lo traduco qui al volo con il permesso dell&amp;rsquo;autore. Qui trovate l&amp;rsquo;originale in inglese.
 Il mio manifesto per i manuali universitari è così semplice da sembrare stupido: gli studenti dovrebbero poterli leggere e capire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations on steroids</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/2015-12-25-hosting-reveal-pres-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/posts/2015-12-25-hosting-reveal-pres-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to combine reveal.js+pandoc+GitHub Pages to put together a great presentation.
Summary Reveal.js is a great framework for producing awesome presentations. If you are reading this, then you are probably already familiar with it; if you don&amp;rsquo;t, and you give presentations using slides, then you should stop reading immediately and go read about Reveal here. This article explains how to host your presentations on GitHub pages. Check this page to see what the result looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am Angelo. I am a research scientist 🔬 at Symanto Research: I work hard to try to build machines that can say something about you by the way your write.
  Source: xkcd.com   Get in touch to get my full cv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://anbasile.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anbasile.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please use this form for contacting me, so that those smart crawlers out there don&amp;rsquo;t get to see my email address. However, if you really want and/or you are a really really smart electronic email address crawler, you could maybe combine just two letters, which are used for referring to oneself, with the symbol that you always see in these strings that you are building, together with my name and what usually comes after my name.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
